<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
  <LocalizedText>
  <!--Civilizations/Leaders -->
    <Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_HYLIAN_NAME" Language="en_US">
      <Text>Hyrule</Text>
    </Row>
   <Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_HYLIAN_DESCRIPTION" Language="en_US">
      <Text>The Kingdom of Hyrule</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_ZELDA_NAME" Language="en_US">
      <Text>Princess Zelda</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_HYLIAN_ADJECTIVE" Language="en_US">
      <Text>Hylian</Text>
    </Row>
   <!--Traits -->
   <Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_SACRED_STONES_NAME" Language="en_US">
      <Text>Sacred Stones</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_SACRED_STONES_DESCRIPTION" Language="en_US">
        <Text>Precious metal resources (Jade, Gypsum, Diamonds, Silver, Pearls) grant +3 [ICON_Faith].</Text>
    </Row>
  
    <Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_GODDESS_HARP_NAME" Language="en_US">
        <Text>Goddess's Harp</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_GODDESS_HARP_DESCRIPTION" Language="en_US">
        <Text>Gain +2 free [ICON_GreatMusician] Great Musician points per turn.</Text>
    </Row>

    <!-- Improvements -->
    <Row Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FAIRY_FOUNTAIN_NAME" Language="en_US">
      <Text>Fairy Fountain</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_FAIRY_FOUNTAIN_DESCRIPTION" Language="en_US">
      <Text>Provides +1 [ICON_Culture] culture, and units on this tile completely heal after standing on it for a full turn.</Text>
    </Row>

    <!-- Units -->
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_HERO_OF_TIME_NAME" Language="en_US">
      <Text>Hero of Time</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_HERO_OF_TIME_DESCRIPTION" Language="en_US">
      <Text>Can be purchased with faith. Powerful Swordsman replacement. Gain one free at the beginning of each new era.</Text>
    </Row>


    <!-- Buildings -->
    <Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_TEMPLE_OF_TIME_NAME" Language="en_US">
      <Text>Temple of Time</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_TEMPLE_OF_TIME_DESCRIPTION" Language="en_US">
      <Text>Temple replacement that can be built after reaching the Astrology Tech. Holds 2 [ICON_GreatWork_Music] Great Work of Music slots, and +1 [ICON_GreatMusician] Great Musician points per turn.</Text>
    </Row>

    <Row Tag="LOC_ZELDA_DOM_TEXT" Language="en_US">
          <Text>This is but one of the legends of which the people speak... Long ago, there existed a kingdom where a golden power lay hidden. It was a prosperous land blessed with green forests, tall mountains, and peace. But one day, a man of great evil found the golden power and took it for himself. With its strength at his command, he spread darkness across the kingdom. But then, when all hope had died, and the hour of doom seemed at hand, a young boy clothed in green appeared as if from nowhere. Wielding the blade of evil's bane, he sealed the dark one away and gave the land light.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]What became of that kingdom? None remain who know.</Text>
    </Row>

   <Row Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_ZELDA" Language="en_US">
      <Text>O, wise Princess Zelda, throughout the ages you have defied evil and bore the burdens of your ancestors without complaint or struggle. Your wisdom has been passed down to you by the Gods, and those same Gods have entrusted you with your nation's fate. They want you to carry forward the power, courage and wisdom that they bestowed upon their chosen prophets and pass it down to the people, all whilst protecting them from the dangers of greed and corruption. Will you accept, Princess Zelda? Will you allow Hyrule to become a civilization that stands the test of time?</Text>
    </Row>

  </LocalizedText>
</GameData>
